PhD Candidate, MSc. Albi Dode

Software Engineer & DPO

Keplerstraße 30/3, 89073 Ulm, Germany | +491638587648 | info@albidode.info

in linkedin.com/in/albidode
albidode.info

Summary

Software Engineer/Developer and Data Protection Officer providing technical support, developing software programs, web sites, giving information security/DPO consulence. I have knowledge in Agile methodology for leading teams in achieving excellence in client satisfaction, productivity, and profitability. Firm mindset with a drive to find solutions to new problems. Strong analytical skills and detailed to project's requirements. Adaption well in groups and a willingness to understand the various roles played by fellow team members. Perform tests and find ways to eliminate bugs in the programs. Build interactive and dynamic websites. Experience with remote projects during master studies. Bachelor in Computer science (State University of New York) and Master in Software Engineering (Mälardalens högskola Västerås).

PhD in "The Development of a generic framework for mobile data sensing and mobile patient intervention" (Universität Ulm).

Work experience

PhD 2019

ESIT & University of Ulm

The Development of a generic framework for mobile data sensing and mobile patient intervention

PHP Developer - BlueScreen

2019 - 2019

* Responsible for writing server-side web application logic * Develop back-end components, connect the application with other web services, and support the front-end developers by integrating their work with the application. CI/CD processes * PHP with Codelgniter.

Technical Writer - Ericsson

2018 - 2019

* Supporting documents to communicate complex and technical information * Explain complex information in a clear and concise manner and working with the staff to ensure accuracy of product functionalities. * ArborText TagTool.

Contribute to the establishment and evolution of the digital organisation.

Work together with the product owner and other team in an agile environment. Investigate and suggest new technologies and solution.

IT and DPO - qPharmetra Sweden

2018 - 2018

* Cisco for cloud management for security, networking, and application control * Inform about security risk for Microsoft products * Gather requirements and identify the costs and the time needed to implement the IT project * Supporting, monitoring and maintaining workplace technology and responding to users' requests for help. *Support for Office365 and Web technologies.

Identify and understand business needs.

 $\label{thm:contribute} Contribute to the establishment and evolution of the digital organisation.$

Maintain and develop/refactor existing software. Perform code reviews.

Lecturer - Albanian University Tirana

2015 - 2015

Lecturer and for one semester in Tirana and Berat for the subjects : Computer Architecture & Web Applications.

IT support - Albanian Psychologists Association

2014 - 2015

* Made a website using in HTML/PHP/MySql and a documentation content management system using Java. * SEO optimization.

Transform abstract problems into concrete roadmaps for new digital solutions.

Design and develop new softwares.

Technical Support Specialist - Albanian Business Partner

2012 - 2014

*Meet with the client to determine customization requirements *Work with client to define the scope of the project *Clarify clients system specifications, understand their specific work practices *Travel to customer's site *Diagnose and refine challenges & opportunities *Help clients with



Skills

Methodology

Agile, Scrum

Testing

Jira, JUnit

Databases

Firebase, Oracle, MS Access, SQL, MySQL

Languages

C++, C#, VB .Net,Java, HTML/PHP/Codelgniter,JS ,Python,R

Applications

Weka, SPSS, Windows & Linux Environment, Active Directory, Exchange / Outlook, MS Office, IDEs: NetBeans, Eclipse, Visual Studio, ArborText, GitLab

Experience

Different merit projects such as :

BusPlanner for Ericsson Sweden - Python, HTML, JS, Firebase

Model-based plugin in Eclipse:Java

Different websites in HTML/PHP/MySql

Jira, JUnit, SPSS, Weka, R - used for my master thesis.

Java,HTML/PHP/MySql,JS,Python,ArborText,GitLab,Cod elgniter and Microsoft Support: Used in work and university studies.

Python: Limited as it has been used in only one project.

My bachelor thesis was written in Java for Android using Eclipse.

C++, C#, VB .Net during bachelor years

Languages

English: C1, Certification TOEFL, IELTS

Italian : Certification Celi B-2

Spanish : B1 Swedish : A1

French : Basic words

German: A2

Certification

GDPR - DPO

change-management activities *Purchase systems where appropriate *Design, test, install and monitor new systems.*Facilitated network support for hospitals in Tirana for a software written in Java. * Supported different troubleshoots within Windows systems.

Introduce and implement relevant framework and tools.

Freelancer

Different websites for private companies using HTML/PHP/MySql.

Education

Bachelor in Computer Science

2010 - 2014

University of New York Tirana & State University of New York

Thesis: Hotel Booking Android application

Master of Science in Software Engineering

2015 - 2017

Mälardalen University

Under Erasmus Mundus Scholarship

Thesis: Effectiveness of fault prediction

Download PDF - DIVA Portal

Thesis conducted at Accedo Broadband AB Stockholm

University Courses

2010 - 2017

Bachelor & Master

- Component-based Technologies
- Industrial System Development
- Research Methods in the Natural Sciences and Engineering
- Abstract Algebra
- Advanced Java
- Algebra
- C++
- Java • Computer Organization
- Composition I/II
- Calculus I/II
- Computer Ethic
- Data communication and networking
- Data structures
- Databases SQL
- Discrete Math
- Distributed Software Development
- Eastern Empires
- Photography
- Linear Algebra
- Mathematics behind internet
- Model-Driven Software Engineering
- Networking
- Operating Systems
- Operations Research
- Physic
- Psychology
- Real time systems
- Software verification and validation
- Security engineering
- Software engineering I/II/III
- Trigonometry • US history I/II
- VB Net
- PHP

Contributions

Certification from FER University for high results in Distributed systems course - 2017.

Finalist at "From Gjirokastra to Gjirokastra" competition - 2014.

Rotary Club Tirana - Charity work for families in needs in Mirdita - 2013.

Core Competencies

- Scrum/Agile
- Project Management
- Troubleshooting
- Analytical skills
- Group work
- Knowledge of intended audience

- Coding
- Technical Support
- Quality Assurance
- · Research in new technologies
- Multitasking
- Adapt in teams with different cultures

Articles and publications

Technology and democratic citizenship connection in Albania - UNIEL - 2014

A.Dode, E.Dode

 $https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Albi_Dode/publication/314235740_Technology_and_democratic_citizenship_connection_in_Albania/links/58bc3f22a6fdcc2d14e58f21/Technology_and_democratic_citizenship_connection_in_Albania/links/58bc3f22a6fdcc2d14e58f21/Technology_and_democratic_citizenship_connection_in_Albania/links/58bc3f22a6fdcc2d14e58f21/Technology_and_democratic_citizenship_connection_in_Albania/links/58bc3f22a6fdcc2d14e58f21/Technology_and_democratic_citizenship_connection_in_Albania/links/58bc3f22a6fdcc2d14e58f21/Technology_and_democratic_citizenship_connection_in_Albania/links/58bc3f22a6fdcc2d14e58f21/Technology_and_democratic_citizenship_connection_in_Albania/links/58bc3f22a6fdcc2d14e58f21/Technology_and_democratic_citizenship_connection_in_Albania/links/58bc3f22a6fdcc2d14e58f21/Technology_and_democratic_citizenship_connection_in_Albania/links/58bc3f22a6fdcc2d14e58f21/Technology_and_democratic_citizenship_connection_in_Albania/links/58bc3f22a6fdcc2d14e58f21/Technology_and_democratic_citizenship_connection_in_Albania/links/58bc3f22a6fdcc2d14e58f21/Technology_and_democratic_citizenship_connection_in_Albania/links/58bc3f22a6fdcc2d14e58f21/Technology_and_democratic_citizenship_connection_in_Albania/links/58bc3f22a6fdcc2d14e58f21/Technology_and_democratic_citizenship_connection_in_Albania/links/58bc3f22a6fdcc2d14e58f21/Technology_and_democratic_citizenship_connection_in_Albania/links/58bc3f22a6fdcc2d14e58f21/Technology_and_democratic_citizenship_connection_in_Albania/links/58bc3f22a6fdcc2d14e58f21/Technology_and_democratic_citizenship_connection_in_Albania/links/58bc3f22a6fdcc2d14e58f21/Technology_and_democratic_citizenship_connection_in_Albania/links/58bc3f22a6fdcc2d14e58f21/Technology_and_democratic_citizenship_connection_in_Albania/links/58bc3f22a6fdcc2d14e58f21/Technology_and_democratic_citizenship_citizenship_citizenship_citizenship_citizenship_citizenship_citizenship_citizenship_citizenship_citizenship_citizenship_citizenship_citizenship_citizenship_citizenship_citizenship_citizenship_citizenship_citi$

The Values of Civic Education through Information Technology- Albanian University – 2015

http://www.mcser.org/journal/index.php/ajis/article/view/7397

https://doi.org/10.5901/ajis.2015.v4n2s2p15

A.Dode, E.Dode

Teenagers Problems Related with Social-Networking - Epoka University - 2015

A Dode, G Rexha, L Nishan

Proceedings of the 5th International Conference on European Studies 5th ICES

http://dspace.epoka.edu.al/handle/1/1316

An Android-based Application for Mining Customer Satisfaction

International Scientific Conference COMPUTER SCIENCE'2015

08-10 September 2015, Durrës, Albania

Albi Dode, Erind Bedalli

http://cs.tu-sofia.bg/conf/ComputerScience15_Program.pdf

NETWORK SECURITY THROUGH VULNERABILITY ANALYSIS

Albi Dode, Silvester Hasani

http://www.inderscience.com/jhome.php?jcode=ijkms

Effectiveness of fault prediction - Review - Albanian University - 2016

Albi Dode, Genta Rexha, Kinan Dindan

http://www.albanianuniversity.al/al/njoftime/401-konferenca-nderkombetare-dhjetor-2016

Assessment of an IT network security with information gathering tools - Albanian University 2015

Albi Dode. Silvester Hasani

 $https://www.researchgate.net/publication/314235536_Assessment_of_an_lT_network_security_with_information_gathering_tools.$

Page Rank Algorithm

Albi Dode, Silvester Hasani

http://www.iosrjournals.org/iosr-jce/pages/19(1)Version-3.html

https://doi.org/10.9790/0661-1901030107

http://journals.indexcopernicus.com/issue.php?id=11660&id_issue=886308

Why do programmers prefer Opencl for Gpu programming? - European University 2016

Albi Dode, Genta Rexha

 $https://www.academia.edu/36823300/Why_do_programmers_prefer_Opencl_for_Gpu_programming$

The challenges of implementing General Data Protection Law (GDPR)

Albi Dode

 $https://www.researchgate.net/publication/327829348_The_challenges_of_implementing_General_Data_Protection_Law_GDPR$

Conferences

